<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Fonzi.xyz</title>
<description>Fonzi.xyz blog. Nothing much of importance here, but will share toughts.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://fonzi.xyz/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://fonzi.xyz/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<!-- LB -->

<item>
<title>TestOps? What is that?</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#testops-what-is-that</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 16:14:08 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en">
<head>
<title></title>
<link rel='stylesheet' type='text/css' href='../styles.css'>
<meta charset='utf-8'/>
</head>
<body>
<h1></h1>
<small>[<a href='../blog.html#testops-what-is-that'>link</a>&mdash;<a href='testops-what-is-that.html'>standalone</a>]</small>
<div class="left">
    <h2 id='testops-what-is-that'>TestOps? What is that?</h2>
    <p>
        A new word is buzzing around. Let me guide you a bit back with buzzwords. The current hot field is DevOps everyone wants to be in DevOps every company needs DevOps. Before that, it used to be two roles. Developer and Operations. Then someone figured out that merging them would be more efficient and a new role was born. Same with TestOps is happening now. 
        Now I think the general tech industry has still not really realized this as a whole. However, more than likely it will be a very big buzz work here soon. At least that's my hope :). 
        Now that Selenium is getting dethroned and frameworks like cypress and playwright are more mature, or even "AI" supported testing tools like Mabl. There is a new need for a role that can truly support a massive amount of tests. This is where the ops part come in. Things like EvoMaster that are auto-generating API tests, still need someone to maintain that infrastructure. 
        DevOps, could fill and will fill a lot of these roles. Here is TestOps will become a trend. DevOps will realize that they need someone who is versed in dev practices and test practices. What kind of tests to implement, and at which part of the pipeline they should run at. 
        Usually testers (manual and automation) do not really get involved in the pipe lining in the full software cycle. However, most will be forced to learn or get pushed out of the industry. 
        Software has become faster and more fierce. So testers need to adapt. The idea of testing at the end of a cycle (I'm looking at you Sprints) is a old way of thinking. Today software teams needs to follow the three main tenants of DevOps. 
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li>Faster flow (push testing to the left)</li>
            <li>Feedback (fast information must be provided to developers)</li>
            <li>CI (Things should be happening when integration takes place and the feedback loop needs to keep moving). This third tenant also has experimentation and learning.</li>
        </ul>
        <br>
        Now once you see the new cycle, you can start to see why the role of TestOps will start to appear. Companies will still be interested in having tests ran. And DevOps really still does not take into consideration testing very much. Nor are most DevOps folks in the mentality of finding edge cases. 
        I'm not one to think that QA will be pushed out of the industry, it'll still exist, just how it exist for manufacturing. However it will become more automated instead of manual, just like it did in manufacturing. 
        Testers should start adopting the tenants of DevOps and a lot of things will become more clear, and they will become exponentially better at their jobs as well. 
        Testers are a rich mine of knowledge when it comes to workflows, which means that they can share a lot of information with OPS on how clients may use the software which may show a much better infrastructure layout. However, the wind blows. The lines are getting blurred here. 
        TestOps will end up been a part of DevOps and they will mainly focus on the CI side. As soon as tests get kicked off as soon as Pull Request or Merge Request come online. Tests should run. But the big question that QA can fill here, is what tests should run there? Or further down to the right. 
        Why do I think TestOps is the next "big" thing? Because we went from water fall, where the initial cycle was defined. To sprints (the most common one right now) that are mini waterfalls. To now the new kids on the block, Kanban and clean room. So the more efficient these cycles become the more broad these roles will become. 
    </p>
</div>
<footer><a href='https://fonzi.xyz/'>Fonzi Vazquez</a></footer>
</body>

</html>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title></title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#ui-automation-root-issues</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 23:55:43 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[

<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en">
<head>
<title>UI Automation Root Issues. </title>
<link rel='stylesheet' type='text/css' href='../styles.css'>
<meta charset='utf-8'/>
</head>
<body>
<h1>UI Automation Root Issues.</h1>
<small>[<a href='../blog.html#ui-automation-root-issues.html'>link</a>&mdash;<a href='ui-automation-root-issues.html'>standalone</a>]</small>
<div class="left">
	<p> Ever since the inception of webapps, there has been issues with UI automation. 
        Teams tend to overlook the automation phase and ignore it. Mostly because it's time consuming and
        it's really hard to have a decent framework. Test are also brittle. However, I peronslly think the brittle-ness 
        is not Automation specific but usually and underlaying issue in the web app. 
        It usually ends up showing up as bad code. Bad implementations, and bad architecture. Since automation 
        is usually created after the webapp, it usually follows those same bad practices as the webapp. 
        Now I'm NOT saying that these are the only issues. But from my experience these are usually the true root issues. 
        <br>
        <br>
        So how do we solve for this. Usually there seems to be three main problems to solve. 
        <ul>
            <li>Bad Architecture</li>
            <li>Bad Implementation</li>
            <li>Bad Infrastructure</li>
        </ul>
        
        <br>
        <br>
        <b>Bad Architecture</b>
        <br>
        Usually this is the first issue. When a webapp has no cohesion around UI and functionality, each page will be it's own
        small domain. This will make it very hard to abstract tests in order to re-use automation methods. 
        The fix here is to get early into the development cycle and try to drive the model that will be used. 
        However, this is easier said that done. Best approach is to point it out to developers in a nice way. 
        However, good architecs are hard to find, so webapps end up displaying very odd functionality. 
        <ul>
            <li>Modals with functionality - This is the terrbile espeially with smooth appearing</li>
            <li>Dropdows with a single button inside - Why is there even a dropdown button for a single button</li>
            <li>Async calls - This is usually where the bad architecture shows itself and it's hardest to debug. 
                Having all the network calls in async, and not understanding how and why they load in certain orders can cause havoc.</li>    
        </ul>

        <b>Bad Implementation</b>
        <br>
        This is usually done when there is some new cool hip JS library (another reason why I hate JS) and it's the modern thing. Developers use 
        the new library. And it's not implemented correctly. Things are getting forced to the way of the webapp instead of the philosophy of the framework. 
        This is usually and issue with developers not giving back to the Opensource Community. They want to take these establish frameworks. Make them work 
        with some very specific need, and instead of making a PR for the framework to support the case, they'll just hack around it. 
        Usually by mixing another framework or another library making another half-assed implementation. 
        <br>
        <br>
        <b>Bad Infrastructure</b>
        <br>
        Now this one is a bit harder to track down, but usually it's obvious once you know what too look for. 
        Usually, bad infrastructure shows as the webapp gets really slow when automation is running. This is usually 
        observable by looking at a Monitoring Tool. Another easy spot is to look at the DB calls that it makes and see if something is locking the db. 
        The final and hardest thing to track down with Infrastructure is the complextity around WAFs. If automation is 
        distributed it might be that the WAF is blocking calls. 
    </p> 
</div>
<footer><a href='https://fonzi.xyz/'>Fonzi Vazquez</a></footer>
</body>

</html>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Node IPC. Going back in time.</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#node-ipc-going-back-in-time</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 18:28:03 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<div class="left">
	<p>Well I'm sure if you follow this blog (if anyone). You most likley heard
	   of node-ipc. This reminds me a lot from when people did not know how malwayre worked, 
	   and the famouse worm that self duplicated by looking up everyone in the email contacts and sending itself out. 
	   What does this recent event says about the current 'software developers' that it affected. It means that they have
	   or at least had no concern about security. They just trusted their projects to one point of failure. A upstream 
	   library gone rouge. How could this been prevented? I think this goes back to the first things that I hinted, central
 	   technologies are a bad idea. Let this be a warning to alaways try to audit some code before you let some critical machine 
           do an update. This is why the most important part of open source code is the abilty to audit the code. 
           Now even this is by definition a new type of malware that has been called "protestware", I disagree with this. 
           How does deleting data from machines that have a Russian IP "protest" anything? What if this "protest" actually deleted work 
           that could had expedited the end of the current Russia v Ukraine war. Or how does punishing every day Russians help them be against
           the war? If anything it'll make them empathetic and start agreeing with the propaganda that the west is indeed out to hurt them personally.
	   Brandon Nozaki Miller has himself pushed out of any career, nor will he ever be able to clear his reputation from this. 
           He has hurted the open source trust and will be used as an example into why normal every day people should not switch from Windows or OSX 
           to linux. Everyone is to blame here. Brandon Nozaki Miller, devs that just merged code into projects without auditing before (or looking
           at the releas notes. I highly suggest checking out <a href="https://github.com/RIAEvangelist/node-ipc/issues">the github issue page</a>
           it is indeed comical, and it is even funnier watching Brandon Nozaki Miller delete the complains. Not only did he screw up and every one 
           knows it, he is censoring opinions about it. To everyone commenting on there it would be better if you do a small snippet like this. 
           No way he can delete this post.
	</p> 
</div>
]]></description>
</item>




<item>
<title>DuckDuckGo Failed Search Engine</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#duckduckgo-failed-search-engine</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 01:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
Well then. Here we are again. Another technology that will fall into the bin of dispair. DuckDuckGo, like all the other big tech companies will eventually die off. 
You have to wonder why they do this to themselves? To me it appears that technologies companies have forgotten their place in the world, and that is that technology moves fast. 
Really fast, and what is hip today, may not be hip tommorow. If you look at previous tech giants like Google, half the population, at least in the US, already despise it.
DuckDuckGo is also in a very bad postion to try to manipulate the search results for mis-information. Most users of DuckDuckGo left Google or Yahoo, or even Bing due to the censorship under those platforms.
Personally, I beleive that users are smart enough to figure out if something if fake, or at least to take it with a grain of salt. 

There is also the issue that DuckDuckGo has forgotten the number one rule when it comes to war. 'The first casualty of war is the truth'
I'm not one to stand on either side of Ukraine or Russia. I like most Americans have no horse in this race, so it should not concern us. However, will the Ukrain news articles also get censored? Has Ukraine never
done propaganda? I doubt it. There is no state in this world that does not produce some form of propaganda, and saying otherwise is lying. 

These recent events just show that me and another small group of people are in the right path to try to detach from this current system of tech giants that control most of the internet services. 
<ul>	
	<li>Host your own website to write down rants like I do.</li> 
	<li>Host your own search engine like I do over at <a href="searx.fonzi.xyz">searx.fonzi.xyz</a></li>
	<li>Host your own instagram.</li>
	<li>Host your own media.</li>
	<li>Host your own chat server.</li>
	<li>Host your own bank.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Facebook down! A warning.</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#facebook-down-a-warning</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
So as you've heard Facebook was down. Not just Facebook, but all of Facebook. Instagram, Whatsapp, Facebook, and some other smaller services. 
	I got to see firsthand how hard this actually was. In the United States, we are pretty lucky that almost every person has a cell phone with data. 
	However, in other countries like Mexico, they use Facebook messenger, and WhatsApp as a means of primary communication.

	Facebook is free of data usage and so it's WhatsApp down in Mexico with almost every plan that you can buy. For this reason, a lot of people use 
	these services instead of using other non-facebook services. The real issue here is not that Facebook is giving their product for free, but rather,
	that people are willing to give all that personal information for just a simple messaging app. Data is a Billion dollar industry. Everyone wants data. 
	And people get hardly any compensation for it because they are not aware of how much data is worth. 

	Protect your data. Don't give it away for free, at least make a little profit.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Blogging Frameworks Are Bloat!</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#blogging-frameworks-are-bloat</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 03:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<div class="left">
		Yes! Blogging Frameworks are bloat. Think about WordPress. Some people install WordPress just to blog. How many issues do you introduce to a website with WordPress?
        Even if you look at other frameworks that are found on Github. They all require some other stack that's never on your server. 
        Then you get stuck in limbo trying to get this framework that has 1000 stars because people star it but never actually try it out. 
        So I ended just doing plain HTML with a little script I found in <a href="https://github.com/lukesmithxyz/lb">github</a>. 
        I still need to modify this a bit, however, it got me off the ground right away. 
        It's gnu compliant so it'll run on any system that has SED and bash. It just inserts blobs of text into files. 
        In my instance, it throws code to blog.html and adds a new file for a standalone blog HTML as well as inserts text to rss.xml. 
        This allows me to just write and not worry about how to run a specific framework, and all the security issues it brings with it. 
        Now I hope that I'll blog more since this is a much easier way to just add files to the blog list. 
        No more manually adding those, no more cryptic commands that only exist in 1 project. This opens the question about what is happening to the tech industry/community. 
        Do developers no longer enjoy simplicity? I can only imagine the things old-timers think when they see all this bloat on pages. 
        Another popular way people do blogging, journalists mostly pay someone else to host their blog so they get an easy WYSIWYG system, but then complain when their freedom of speech is taken because they never actually owned the blog. 
        It's on someone else server. Their rules at that point. I do hope that this, what I'm doing having a very minimal website takes off again, what's better than going back to decentralization with what already exists until the blockchain can fully be adopted if it's ever adopted.  
</div>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title> 
Hello There!</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#hello-there</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 02:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
	<div class="left">
		<p> If you ended up here either you agreed with something on the homepage. Or you're just clicking around. Either way.. Hello!
		This blog is dedicated to things I find interesting. Things about technology most of the time, but I also enjoy sociology a lot. So writing about human interactions maybe something from time to time. 
		Also, you will find just recommendations for different things. This will mostly be something for me but I will try to curate those lists.  You will also find quick lessons I've learned. This blog also follows
		the minimalist web theme. Where I don't have a blogging platform besides SSH a terminal and my thoughts. So you will just see new entries here without sorting or anything. Perhaps in the future, I'll add something 
		like that along with RSS to keep this going. One of my biggest pet peeves is trying to do a blog site. Imagine my shock when I looked through countless GitHub repositories just looking for something that allowed me
		to just write and would auto-publish, after hours I found nothing that's simple enough. Every technology for this sort of stuff has a very very very complex mechanism for what they do. Take a look. You'll find things 
		like a specific language for just that one blogging platform with no other uses. The worst thing is that it had about 1k stars. What is going on in the modern technology field? Do we no longer like elegant simple solutions?
		I have an idea to write about this bloated software and how I think modern society has shaped this. 
			</p>
	</div>
]]></description>
</item>




</channel>
</rss>