<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Fonzi.xyz</title>
<description>Fonzi.xyz blog. Nothing much of importance here, but will share toughts.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://fonzi.xyz/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://fonzi.xyz/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<!-- LB -->

<item>
<title> 
Hello There!</title>
<guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog.html#hello-there</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 02:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
	<div class="left">
		<p> If you ended up here either you agreed with something on the homepage. Or you're just clicking around. Either way.. Hello!
		This blog is dedicated to things I find interesting. Things about technology most of the time, but I also enjoy sociology a lot. So writing about human interactions may be something from time to time. 
		Also you will find just recommendations for different things. This will mostly be a something for myself but I will try to curate those list.  You will also find quick lessons I've learned. This blog also follows
		the minimalist web theme. Where I don't have a bloggin platform besides SSH a terminal and my taughts. So you will just see new entries here without sorting or anything. Perphaps in the future I'll add something 
		like that along with RSS to keep this going. One of my biggest pet-peeves is trying to do a blog site. Imagine my shock when I looked through countless github repositories just looking for something that allowed me
		to just write and would auto-publish, after hours I found nothing that's simple enough. Every technology for this sort of stuff has very very very complex mechanism for what they do. Take a look. You'll find things 
		like a specific language for just that one bloggin platform with no other uses. Worst thing is that is had about 1k stars. What is going on in the modern technology field? Do we no longer like elegant simple solutions?
		I have an idea to write about this bloated software and how I think modern society has shaped this. 
		</p>
	</div>
]]></description>
</item>




</channel>
</rss>