<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Fonzi Vazquez</title>
    <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Fonzi Vazquez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 19:22:56 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fonzi.xyz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pipelining Qa in Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/pipelining-qa-in-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 19:22:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/pipelining-qa-in-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been about 3 months that I switched from Github over to Gitlab. At my previous job. I had to use github actions for pipeline. Now I use Gitlab. I can honestly say that Github is 100 times better and more intuative on how it works. As well as the market place is a great resource. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if Gitlab has something like that built into their roadmap. However, I keep writing code that I know other people have solved, because I find it in gitlab threads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprints Are Bad For Every Department in Modern Software</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/sprits-are-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 09:10:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/sprits-are-bad/</guid>
      <description>Sprints. Everyone uses them it seems like. However, there is a reason why there are new ways of developing software. Sprints are waterfalls in essence. Methodologies like Kanban really outshine sprints. In modern software development where you can create infrastructure in IaC and Deploy with tools like AWS / GitHub / Pipeline. These modern tools allow you to deploy faster, which is what every company claims they want to do, but never actually break out of the mold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatgpt and QA</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/chatgpt-and-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 10:54:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/chatgpt-and-qa/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT. Speeding up every part of the SDLC If you read this blog, then you have heard of ChatGPT. AI for the masses. You know, a lot of people are saying it&amp;rsquo;s the end of software development as we know it, but are they right? I think it&amp;rsquo;s just another tool to help speed up development. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we are at the location where jobs can be fully replaced. Yet&amp;hellip; So how has it increased the SDLC speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I switched to Hugo?</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/hugo-ftw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 14:51:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/hugo-ftw/</guid>
      <description>Why I switched to Hugo? If you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed at all. The page has changed drastically. I switched from hand cranked HTML and CSS into Hugo! Found that there is a decent blogging platform out there that is lightweight.
Writing in markdown files, and just having it generate static HTML is great. No dealing with JS/CSS/HTML anymore. However, a framework does it. The nice thing about it is that there is no heavy JS on the server nor client side to render a neat little page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestOps? What is that?</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/testopts-what-is-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 16:14:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/testopts-what-is-that/</guid>
      <description>TestOps? What is that? A new word is buzzing around. Let me guide you a bit back with buzzwords. The current hot field is DevOps everyone wants to be in DevOps every company needs DevOps. Before that, it used to be two roles. Developer and Operations. Then someone figured out that merging them would be more efficient and a new role was born. Same with TestOps is happening now. Now I think the general tech industry has still not really realized this as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UI Automation Root Issues</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/ui-automation-root-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 23:55:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/ui-automation-root-issues/</guid>
      <description>UI Automation Root Issues Ever since the inception of webapps, there has been issues with UI automation. Teams tend to overlook the automation phase and ignore it. Mostly because it&amp;rsquo;s time consuming and it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to have a decent framework. Test are also brittle. However, I peronslly think the brittle-ness is not Automation specific but usually and underlaying issue in the web app. It usually ends up showing up as bad code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node IPC. Going back in time.</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/node-ipc-going-back-in-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 18:35:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/node-ipc-going-back-in-time/</guid>
      <description>Node IPC Going Back in Time Well I&amp;rsquo;m sure if you follow this blog (if anyone). You most likley heard of node-ipc. This reminds me a lot from when people did not know how malwayre worked, and the famouse worm that self duplicated by looking up everyone in the email contacts and sending itself out. What does this recent event says about the current &amp;lsquo;software developers&amp;rsquo; that it affected. It means that they have or at least had no concern about security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo Failed Search Engine</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/dudkduckgo-failed-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 01:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/dudkduckgo-failed-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>DuckDuckGo Failed Search Engine Well then. Here we are again. Another technology that will fall into the bin of dispair. DuckDuckGo, like all the other big tech companies will eventually die off. You have to wonder why they do this to themselves? To me it appears that technologies companies have forgotten their place in the world, and that is that technology moves fast. Really fast, and what is hip today, may not be hip tommorow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook down! A warning.</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/facebook-down-a-warning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/facebook-down-a-warning/</guid>
      <description>Facebook down! A warning. So as you&amp;rsquo;ve heard Facebook was down. Not just Facebook, but all of Facebook. Instagram, Whatsapp, Facebook, and some other smaller services. I got to see firsthand how hard this actually was. In the United States, we are pretty lucky that almost every person has a cell phone with data. However, in other countries like Mexico, they use Facebook messenger, and WhatsApp as a means of primary communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Frameworks Are Bloat</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/blogging-frameworks-are-bloat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 03:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/blogging-frameworks-are-bloat/</guid>
      <description>Blogging Frameworks Are Bloat Yes! Blogging Frameworks are bloat. Think about WordPress. Some people install WordPress just to blog. How many issues do you introduce to a website with WordPress? Even if you look at other frameworks that are found on Github. They all require some other stack that&amp;rsquo;s never on your server. Then you get stuck in limbo trying to get this framework that has 1000 stars because people star it but never actually try it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello There</title>
      <link>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/hello-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 02:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fonzi.xyz/blog/hello-there/</guid>
      <description>Hello There If you ended up here either you agreed with something on the homepage. Or you&amp;rsquo;re just clicking around. Either way.. Hello! This blog is dedicated to things I find interesting. Things about technology most of the time, but I also enjoy sociology a lot. So writing about human interactions maybe something from time to time. Also, you will find just recommendations for different things. This will mostly be something for me but I will try to curate those lists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>